all right anna let's warm up a little
bit
how long has it been since we've been
training when was our first
first lesson was what do you think three
months three months ago
go on the service line
let's back up you're playing well
here we go forehand oh i love it look at
that looping action
so much better
go again nice
big fan of your backhand up up up go
anna your backhand is good but we can do
a couple of things to make it even
better
and one thing that you do sometimes on
your backhand is that you are
kind of bending the forearm and bending
the wrist like this
like this you're kind of muscling the
ball using the arms in isolation without
anything else happening you see so what
you you should do on the backhand is
lead with a dominant elbow as you're
finishing so the
dominant elbow leads the way and you're
going to continue to rotate until
the elbow is pointing towards the back
fence try it out
keep going even more there you go really
yes
right but you don't ha this front elbow
not so high because this is unnecessary
you can keep it a little bit lower
but you go all the way you ever play
golf
i tried one time one time there's
somebody in the comments that was
claiming that you were a golfer
no he saw you play i'm gonna go yeah but
anyway the reason why i bring up golf is
kind of similar to the drive with the
way they finish in golf
is kind of the same like this so that's
how you want to finish on the back end
like rotate as far as your body allows
to
yeah like that rotate as far as you can
go
now what this is gonna do it's gonna
make the backhand more effortless it's
gonna take a lot of pressure off your
arms
it's gonna give you more power and it'll
make it more consistent as well
all right anna let's try to rotate a
little bit more on that backhand okay
it's gonna help you out a lot it's going
to make it easier see that elbow
the right elbow needs to go further you
see how it's kind of stopping
right here like this it needs to
continue going even further than that
meaning like this look just focus on my
right elbow watch this you see where
it's going
all the way back yours is kind of like
here
it's here it stops like this yeah i'll
show you one more time
watch and i want you to really pay
attention to my
right elbow you see it goes right here
like that that's how you have to
that's how you have to finish
better and again
wow so nice that back end excellent
very nice that works right it works
really well
you feel like the ball is going a little
bit faster i think so
okay where did you hit yourself
that low when i hit myself on the back
and i get to about right here
shoulder blade oh you're taller oh yeah
maybe i have a
i have a long uh long torso here try it
again
beautiful backhand nice come again
so clean
okay one thing i don't like what i see
now is this well look
you're going here and you're kind of
keeping this this arm straight here
you have to contract both arms on the
two-handed backhand you know what i mean
by contract
it's like lifting dumbbells you got to
contract the arms see that's no good
this is no good
bring him back and contract both arms
contract
pull this way watch you come here and
you contract
you don't want to keep it straight there
you go that's it it's going to help you
to accelerate and it's also going to
help the swing path
do it again there it is
wow look how much power you're getting
now
look at that okay now try a few on the
run
come nice one
wow that's so good okay a little bit
early there wait longer
yeah finish it all the way
okay now you don't want to spin in a
circle like that because you'll lose
balance super fast
and you reduce the radius of your stroke
so you want to kind of be
a little bit wider base and then don't
allow to spin around your
right leg like this watch you can come
around like this
this is okay but don't allow this to
happen
that's all right come again
and accelerate it's all right to
accelerate accelerate freely
go ahead come on don't be scared hit
that thing
all right one more thing we have to set
on the backhand is the amount of turn so
when you set up you have to turn
so that if you had a number on your back
you want to show that to me okay
if you're wearing a jersey you want to
show me the number on your back like
this you want to make a big shoulder
turn
i'm standing right in front of you kind
of
yeah but not that much not that much oh
watch this is the amount of turn that i
want you to make
now in addition to that you can also
bend the front shoulder down a little
bit okay
you can bend it down like that you see
what i'm doing
this is the setup on the backhand and
now when you accelerate this is going to
straighten a little bit okay
but that's going to happen naturally as
you hit it seems like the
right shoulder is a little down it is
down yes it's a diff of the right
shoulder
and again down with the shoulder good
come on
down with the shoulder that was maybe
the best one you hit so far
come all the way to the middle no
cheating please go again
come on all the way to the middle and
turn and rip this one
i want you to rip a couple of them okay
rip it yeah
that was all arms there you see yes so
what happens if you do a backhand where
the arms are just moving in isolation
meaning nothing else is happening with
the body you get no power
and you might actually feel strained so
this is why you have to
help the swing path with the torso okay
you have to allow the body to rotate
it's kind of like still okay the
rotation
can't happen simultaneously with a
stroke
because then you're just going to spin
in a circle so there's a little bit of a
delay
and the legs are going to come at the
very end always
any stroke antennas the legs always
rotate at the very end if the legs are
rotating together with the strokes
you're going to look like this
yeah you don't want that so the legs
come later it's it's
it's from top down okay so you go here
rotate here first and now the legs come
at the end
you see the way this looks versus this
see this is too much
all right look at this top first and
then towards the bottom here
and here at the very end you allow this
leg to come around
nice one come on that was so clean i
love that backhand nice
go hard on this one
so good anna so good nice job
oh maybe the best one you hit so far
okay a little bit more heat come on give
me some heat
better i'll finish it off in style right
here come on
okay i'm gonna accelerate all the way to
the middle you know what you're not
going to the middle anna i'm gonna have
to get a cone
this is a punishment all right i'll put
it right here
you're very strict coach
much better on and again come on
lift it all the way
better i like that and again come
much better and again come on
this is so good keep going you get into
a groove
there it is again you're back and around
the cone
good oh that's so crisp right there but
i've been telling you to do that you're
not listening to me here we go come on
three more
don't push oh i want you to do two in a
row without missing two in a row
here we go come on so clean and give me
one more
again anna this is unbelievable
great job good backhands it's registered
definitely yeah
you see now it's loaded it's all
downloaded and now it's all sinking in
beautifully and you're hitting the
backhand much better
all right give me a racket tap good job
ana